Matthew Cottrell

ClassicCottrell.ca

ClassicCottrell@gmail.com

**** 778-232-4629



About

My name is Matt and I'm a UI/UX designer. I've been in the software industry for 5 years. When I'm not at work, I'm either involved in film production, drawing weird cartoon characters, or reminiscing about my printing days, when I had access to a vinyl plotter, huge screens and endless rolls of paper.

Experience

- 5 years in a start-up environment
- Experienced in agile development
- Positive personality & dedicated learner
- Adapts easily to new situations & people
- I work well independently, however, I love working in a team environment & brainstorming with my colleagues.

Skills EXPERIANCE OUT OF 5 Work History Tagga - Creative Lead UI/UX Design - HTML, CSS UI/UX Lead 2016 - present - Foundation, Bootstrap, SASS, LESS - User stories, site mapping, conception of new platform tools - Adobe Experience design - Creation of low fidelity to high fidelity designs through - User testing & platform maintenance wireframes, sketches, design, mockups, prototyping (pencil - Content First & responsive design paper, adobe XD) - Email template creation 000 - Software theme & branding, element styles (color exploration, - Campaign Monitor & MailChimp fonts, icons) - Facebook Ad Manager - Google Adwords 0000

Lead Design UI/UX 2011 - 2016

- User experience flow creation
- User Interface front-end development
- Cross channel campaign strategy
- Design & creation of media for campaigns (in-store print design, facebook/ Instagram/twitter social posts, & responsive websites)
- Front end development and QA for site deployments
- Social community creation
- Social posting and storytelling

Intern 2011

- Video production

Art & Design - Adobe Creative suite

- Photoshop	
- Illustrator	••••
- InDesign	•••00
- Final Cut & After Effects	•••00
- Lighting & Set design	••000
- Classical 2D animation	••000
- Stop motion & Cinemagraphs GIF's	••••

C2 Imaging 2000 - 2010

- Sign maker
- Large format digital print operator
- Lün cutter press operator
- Saturn 5 colour printing press assistant

Print & Layout

- Sign maker (layout and quality control)	••••
- 5 color printing process	•••00
- T-shirt printing process	•••00
- Store Front vinyl sign application	•••00
- Zün (digital die-cutting)	•••00
- Prepress knowledge & understanding	•••00

Education and Training

BCIT - New Media Design & Web Development Certificate2010 - 2011Vancouver Film School - Foundation in Film & Design2006 - 2007Langley Fine Arts School - Fine Arts Major2001 - 2004